Brandon Touchet | Resume

PO Box 771021 – Steamboat Springs, CO 80487

③ 337.356.7298 • ☑ touchetbrandon@gmail.com

☐ brandontouchet.com

Skills

Ansys, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, C++, COMSOL, CSS, HTML, Inkscape jQuery, Matlab, Mathematica, Mendeley, LATEX, Octave, PowerBI, PYTHON, SQL, Tableau

Experience

Scientific Data Analysis Researcher

Biodesix

2017-Present
Steamboat Springs, Colorado

Instructor of Physics2017-PresentColorado Community Colleges OnlineColorado

Graduate Researcher 2012–2016
Louisiana Tech University Ruston, Louisiana

Consultant 2011–2012

Beta Land Services, LLC Colorado, Illinois, Ohio, Louisiana, Wyoming

Education

Louisiana Tech University

PhD Engineering Physics

Louisiana Tech University

MS Applied Physics

Cuniversity of Louisiana

BS Physics

Ruston, LA

Ruston, LA

Ruston, LA

Ruston, LA

Ruston, LA

Lafayette, LA

Highlights

Biodesix: Responsibilities are wide-ranging but generally consist of quality control and assessment of clinical mass spectrometers and the spectra they produce, data visualization, data mining, metric development, project management, and analysis of our research approaches. I have also developed a novel averaging method that improves resolution and reduces noise of clinical, Deep MALDI spectra and a real-time monitoring tool (integrated with Tableau visualization software) for mass spectrometers. This tool quantifies and qualifies machine state, forecasts mechanical machine issues, and assist with machine tuning.

PhD: I was able to classically resolve the electron self-energy paradox $(E(electron) \neq mc^2)$ through the notion of space being non-empty. Further implications show quantum-like phenomena from the classical scale that also agree with experiment. This is the first classical theorem that can successfully account for pair annihilation (electron+positron='BOOM'), as is commonly encountered with PET imaging.

Beta Land Services: Built a centralized SCRUM style database for land analysis reports and associated documents while managing a team of 30 people in the busiest oil county in Colorado. I was subsequently sent on high priority projects in Wyoming, Illinois, Ohio, and Louisiana.

ULL: Performed research on characterization of metal alloy elastic properties, dark matter via statistical analysis of Type Ia supernova data, and developed non-incendiary tracers for the US Army. The tracers are now commercially available at Cabela's and online as "Glow Ammo" and involved building a "dark tunnel" to test the munitions, operating heavy machinery, welding, electrical, and munitions manufacturing.